# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hi everyone, This is Chef Wang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'll share a homely dish with you
# 红油腰花
"red oil kidneys“
# 首先我们准备新鲜的猪腰几个
First we prepare a few fresh pig's kidneys
# 从中间片开之后平刀去掉腰骚备用
cut in the middle, remove all white fascias
# 建议新手同学交给摊主来处理
It is recommended that for a novice you better ask the meat seller to do this step for you.
# 否则有可能猪腰会所剩无几
Otherwise there may be little kidneys left.
# 筋膜去除干净之后下一步开始准备切腰花
After removing all white fascias, next we are going to cut the kidneys into flower-like shape.
# 首先我们斜刀切进猪腰的4分之3
We slantly cut into the kidney 3/4.
# 同学们这一步既要切深一些但也不能切断
This step must cut deep enough but not cut off.
# 然后将猪腰倒过来竖着斜刀切出腰花
Then change a direction slant-cut the kidney into flower-like shape.
# 这两步都必须尽量把刀倾斜起来
Both steps must tilt the knife as much as possible
# 角度倾斜得越大切出来的腰花则越长
The greater the angle of tilting, the longer the flower-like shape will be.
# 然后将切好的猪腰翻面切成小条备用
Then turn the kidney over and cut it into small strips.
# 下一步开始准备初加工
Next step is preliminary processing
# 碗中加入适量的啤酒将腰花浸泡10分钟备用
Add moderate amount of beer to the bowl, soak the kidney flowers for 10 minutes.
# 这一步的目的是去除猪腰的骚味
The purpose of this step is to remove the smell of kidneys.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, prepare assistant ingredients
# 准备莴笋200克切成细丝备用
Prepare 200g lettuce and cut into fine shreds
# 不喜欢莴笋的同学也可以用青瓜丝代替
Those who do not like lettuce can use cucumber instead,
# 还可以用焯熟的绿豆芽代替
and can also use boiled mung-bean sprouts instead.
# 笋丝切好之后加入食用盐1小勺搅拌均匀腌制5分钟备用
When lettuce shreds are prepared, add 1 teaspoon of salt, mix them together, marinate for 5 minutes.
# 这一步的目的是去除笋丝中的生水
The purpose of this step is to remove water from lettuce.
# 5分钟之后捞出挤干水分垫底备用
5 minutes later, squeeze out the water, then put them in the bottom of the bowl
# 下一步开始调红油
Next, prepare red oil
# 准备大蒜2颗拍散之后剁碎备用
Prepare 2 garlic pieces and crush them up
# 准备小葱头几根拍散之后切碎备用
Prepare a few green onions and chop them up
# 最后准备适量的香菜根剁碎备用
Finally, prepare an appropriate amount of cilantro roots, chop them up.
# 同学们香菜梗必须清洗干净否则会有泥沙
Cilantro roots must be carefully cleaned, otherwise there are remaining fine sands.
# 碗中加入食用盐0.5克
Add 0.5g of salt into the bowl
# 加入少许白糖
Add a little white sugar
# 加入陈醋1克
Add 1g of vinegar
# 加入生抽酱油5克
Add 5g of light soy sauce
# 最后加入香辣红油50克
In the end, add 50g of spicy red oil, mix them together
# 搅拌均匀之后下一步开始处理腰花
Next deal with the kidneys
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水开大火烧开
First, we add the right amount of water into the pot and boil it
# 中途加入适量的料酒
# Add the right amount of Chinese cooking wine during the heating
# 然后将腌制好的猪腰倒出沥干啤酒
Then pour out the marinated kidneys and drain the beer
# 用清水清洗干净之后挤干水份
Rinse it with clean water and squeeze water out
# 挤干水份之后加入少许食用盐搅拌均匀（上底味）
After squeezing out the water, add a little salt and mix them well (to increase the base taste)
# 最后再加入1小把土豆淀粉拌匀
Finally add 1 small handful of potato starch and mix them well
# 这一步的目的是让腰花保持嫩度和爽脆
The purpose of this step is to keep the kidneys tender and crisp
# 拌匀之后将腰花下入烧开的水中
Then put the kidneys into the boiling water
# 然后待水再次开起来10秒钟即可倒出
Wait for the water to boil again, then pour kidneys out in 10 seconds
# 同学们切记猪腰不能煮太久否则不嫩
Remember that the kidneys can't be cooked too long or it won't taste tender
# 此刀法切的腰花10秒钟足以煮熟所以不必担心
10 seconds is long enough to cook well the kidneys that are cut by this knife skill, so don't worry about it.
# 沥干水份之后将腰花摆盘
After draining out the water, place the kidneys on the plate
# 最后再淋上调好的红油料（汁）即可上菜
Finally, drizzle the prepared red oil to serve
# 一道非常美味的红油腰花就制作完成
A very delicious dish "red oil kidneys" is finished
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，必须选择微白粉红的猪腰，凡是发黑有淤血的猪腰均为死猪或者病猪
# 第二，不会切腰花的同学可以直接切成小片
# 第三，猪腰下锅之前必须加入盐和干淀粉拌匀，这样成菜才足够鲜嫩爽脆
# 红油腰花 的技术总结完毕
# The technical summary is as below,
# First, you must choose the pig's kidneys that are slightly white and pink.
# Any black and bruised kidney is from the dead or sick pig.
# Second, those who don't know how to cut kidneys into flower-like shape can directly cut into small pieces.
# Third, Before cooking the kidneys, salt and dry starch must be added and mixed well, so that the dish is fresh and crisp.
# That's the technical summary of "red oil kidneys".